Forget Everything You Have Ever Seen...
Santa Sangre is a thriller, drama, horror film directed by Alejandro Jodorowsky.
A former circus artist escapes from a mental hospital to rejoin his armless, cult
leader mother, and is forced to enact brutal murders in her name.
Fenix, played by Axel Jodorowsky.
Concha, played by Blanca Guerra.
Orgo, played by Guy Stockwell.
The Tattooed Woman, played by Thelma Tixou.
Alma, played by Sabrina Dennison.
Young Fenix, played by Adan Jodorowsky.
Santa Sangre (Spanish pronunciation: [ˈsãn̪.t̪a ˈsãŋ.ɡɾe], 'Holy Blood') is a 1989 surrealist psychological horror film
directed by Alejandro Jodorowsky and written by Jodorowsky along with Claudio Argento and Roberto Leoni.
It stars Axel Jodorowsky, Adán Jodorowsky, Teo Jodorowsky,
Blanca Guerra, Thelma Tixou, and Guy Stockwell.
An international co-production of Mexico and Italy, the film is set in Mexico, and tells the story
of Fénix, a boy who grew up in a circus and his struggle with childhood trauma.
It is included in Empire magazine's 2008 list of
the 500 Greatest Movies of All Time.
The film explores themes of suicide, mexico city,
mexico, elephant, funeral, circus.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and emotional.